<problem display_name="Lab 06 Graded Task 1" markdown="null" max_attempts="5" showanswer="past_due" submission_wait_seconds="5" weight="1.0">
  <text>
    <p>
      <u>Description</u>
    </p>
    <p>
In this lab exercise, you are tasked to complete the <b>readWordList()</b> method in the <b>Hangman</b> class. This method reads a word list file and initializes a word list String array. Finally, it returns the number of words read.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Assumptions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>
Each line in the word list file contains one word only with no space.
</li>
        <li>
All words in the word list are in lower case.
</li>
        <li>
There are at most 128 words in the word list file.
</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Instructions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>
Open the file specified by the parameter, <b>fileName</b>, of the method.
</li>
        <li>
Read each line of the file and assign each line to a new position in the <b>wordList</b> array given as one of the method's parameters; i.e. assign the first read line to the first position of the array, the second line to the second position of the array ... etc.
</li>
        <li>
Return the number of words read from the file. You may wish to declare a local <b>int</b> variable for this purpose.
</li>
        <li>
You can assume that the import statements: <b>import java.io.File;</b> and <b>import java.util.Scanner;</b> have been added.  
</li>
        <li>
You may also add your own words to the word list file. Please make sure that the last line of the file should not be empty.
</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Coding Area</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab_06_ca1.png" width="100%"/>
    </p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="hkust_java">
    <textbox rows="9" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4" label="lab06gt1input1"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
// Please write your code after this line
</initial_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"refid": "/comp102x/lab06/ex01", "version":"V-01-20140806", "edge":false }
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation: </p>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Sample Answer</u>
        <br/>
      </p>
      <p>
        <pre>
int numberOfWordsLoaded = 0;

File file = new File(fileName);
Scanner scanner = new Scanner(file);

while (scanner.hasNextLine())
{
	String line = scanner.nextLine();
	wordList[numberOfWordsLoaded++] = line;
}
        
scanner.close();
        
return numberOfWordsLoaded;
</pre>
      </p>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Common Mistakes</u>
        <br/>
        <ol>
          <li>
Creating a Scanner object by using the <b>fileName</b> parameter directly instead of creating a File object first.
</li>
          <li>
Returning the length of the wordList array to be the number of words read from the file.
</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><u>BlueJ Project of the sample answer</u><br/><br/>
You may download the BlueJ Project for the above sample 

answer <a href="/static/Lab_06_Sol.zip">here</a>.
<br/>
</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
