<problem display_name="Lab 04 Graded Task 3" markdown="null" max_attempts="5" showanswer="past_due" submission_wait_seconds="5" weight="2.0">
  <text>
    <p>
      <u>Description</u>
    </p>
    <p>
In this lab exercise, you are tasked to complete the <b>makeChoice()</b> method in the <b>Computer</b> class. This method selects from rock, paper or scissors randomly and updates the computer’s choice.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Instructions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>
Select from 0, 1 or 2 randomly to imitate the computer making a random choice between rock, paper and scissors.
</li>
        <li>
A Random object can be created to select random integers in a specified range. For example, to generate a random integer between 0 (inclusive) and 10 (exclusive), you can code the following:<br/>
<br/>
<pre>
Random randomObject = new Random();
int randomInteger  = randomObject.nextInt(10);  
</pre>
<br/>
You can assume that the Random class has already been imported in the grader.
</li>
        <li>
Assign a new Choice instance to the instance variable choice of the Computer instance according to the random integer generated. You can use the Choice constructor that takes 1 integer argument for creating the new Choice instance.
</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Testing</u>
    </p>
    <p>
A testing class, <b>Lab04GradedTask3</b>, has been prepared for you to test the implementation of the <b>makeChoice()</b> method. To perform testing, right click on the <b>Lab04GradedTask3</b> class and then run the <b>testCase1()</b> method. The expected output of <b>testCase1()</b> is shown below.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Code in testCase1()</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <pre>
Computer computer = new Computer();
computer.makeChoice();
int result = computer.getChoice().getType();
IO.outputln(result);
</pre>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Expect output of testCase1()</u>
    </p>
    <p>
Because of the randomness of this method, there is no specific output. However, only values of 0, 1 or 2 will be output on the screen for a correct implementation for different runs of the <b>testCase1()</b> method.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Coding Area</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab04gt3.png" width="100%"/>
    </p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="hkust_java">
    <textbox rows="9" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4" label="lab04gt3input1"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
// write your code after this line
</initial_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"refid": "/comp102x/lab04/ex03", "version":"V-01-20140716", "edge":false }
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation: </p>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Sample Answer</u>
        <br/>
      </p>
      <pre>
Random random = new Random();
int type = random.nextInt(3);
choice = new Choice(type);
</pre>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Common Mistakes</u>
        <br/>
        <ol>
          <li>Using the <b>nextInt(int)</b> of the Random class method with an incorrect bound. e.g. nextInt(2)</li>
          <li>Assigning the new Choice instance to a local variable instead of the instance variable <b>choice</b> defined.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><u>BlueJ Project of the sample answer</u><br/><br/>
You may download the BlueJ Project for the above sample 

answer <a href="/static/Lab_04_Sol.zip">here</a>.
<br/>
</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
