<problem display_name="Lab 05 Graded Task 4" markdown="null" max_attempts="5" showanswer="past_due" submission_wait_seconds="5" weight="1.0">
  <text>
    <p>
      <u>Description</u>
    </p>
    <p>
In this lab exercise, you are tasked to complete the <b>checkAllMatchesFound()</b> method in the <b>GameBoard</b> class of the <b>2D array matching game</b>. This method determines whether all matching cards have been found by checking if all <b>Card</b> objects have been flipped facing up.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Instructions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>
  Search through the 2D cards array and return <b>true</b> if all the <b>Card</b> objects have been flipped facing up. Otherwise, return <b>false</b>.
</li>
        <li>
To determine the total number of rows and the total number of cards per row in the 2D array, you can use the static variables <b>NUMBER_OF_ROWS</b> and <b>NUMBER_OF_CARDS_PER_ROW</b> defined in the <b>MatchingGame</b> class respectively.
</li>
        <li>
To determine whether a <b>Card</b> object is flipped facing up, use the <b>isFacingUp()</b> method in the <b>Card</b> class.
</li>
        <li>
With a correct implementation of the method, a congratulations message should be displayed on the screen when all matching cards are found.
</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Coding Area</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab_task_4_ca.png" width="100%"/>
    </p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="hkust_java">
    <textbox rows="9" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4" label="lab05gt4input1"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
// Please write your code after this line
</initial_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"refid": "/comp102x/lab05/ex04", "version":"V-01-20140730", "edge":false }
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation: </p>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Sample Answer</u>
        <br/>
      </p>
      <pre>
for(int i = 0; i &lt; MatchingGame.NUMBER_OF_ROWS; i++)
{
	for(int j = 0; j &lt; MatchingGame.NUMBER_OF_CARDS_PER_ROW; j++)
	{
		if(!cards[i][j].isFacingUp()) return false;
	}
}

return true;
</pre>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Common Mistakes</u>
        <br/>
        <ol>
          <li>Checking if the <b>SAME</b> card is flipped up in loop. A correct implementation should check if <b>ALL</b> the cards are flipped up.</li>
          <li>Return <b>true</b> immediately once a card is found flipped up but ignoring all the remaining cards.</li>
          <li>Attempting to use a single <b>break</b> statement to break out of two for loops.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><u>BlueJ Project of the sample answer</u><br/><br/>
You may download the BlueJ Project for the above sample 

answer <a href="/static/Lab_05_2D_Sol.zip">here</a>.
<br/>
</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
