<problem markdown="null" max_attempts="5" submission_wait_seconds="5" weight="2.0" display_name="Lab 02 Graded Task 2" showanswer="past_due">
  <text>
    <p>
      <u>Description</u>
    </p>
    <p>In this lab exercise, you are tasked to write a piece of Java code to calculate the area of a triangle using the formula:
    </p>
    <p>Triangle area = width x height / 2 </p>
    <p>The calculated result is then outputted on the screen.</p>
    <p>
      <u>Instructions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>The Java code should first ask the user to input the width of the triangle by outputting a message on the screen. The format of the message must be <code>Enter the width of the triangle: </code>. Notice that the message ends with a colon followed by a space (i.e. ": ") and the printing position should <b>not</b> be moved to a new line. The program will then allow the user to input the width of the triangle. After that, the inputted width from the user is stored by using a variable.</li>
        <li>Repeat the previous step to get the height of the triangle.</li>
        <li>Calculate the area of the triangle using the formula indicated above, after getting the width and the height. Store the result by using a variable.</li>
        <li>Lastly, output a message on the screen to report the calculated area. The format of the message must be <code>The triangle area = <i>calculated_area</i></code>, with <i>calculated_area</i> replaced by the result obtained. Notice that there must be an equal sign followed by a space (i.e. "= ") just before the <i>calculated_area</i> in the message.</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Sample Input/Output</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab_02_graded_task_2_sample.png"/>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Coding Area</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab_02_gt2_ca.png"/>
    </p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="hkust_java">
    <textbox rows="10" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
// Please write your code after this line
</initial_display>
      <grader_payload>
		{"refid": "/comp102x/lab02/ex02",  "version":"V-01-20140627", "edge":false }
	</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation: </p>
      <br/>
      <p><u>Sample Answer</u><br/><br/>
        IO.output("Enter the width of the triangle: ");<br/>
        int width = IO.inputInteger();<br/>
        <br/>
        IO.output("Enter the height of the triangle: ");<br/>
        int height = IO.inputInteger();<br/>
        <br/>
        double calculated_area = width * height / 2.0;<br/>
        IO.outputln("The triangle area = " + calculated_area);<br/>
      	<br/>
	</p>
      <p>
        <u>Common Mistakes</u>
        <br/>
        <ol>
          <li>Calculating the area of the triangle using integer division, e.g. 3 * 5 / 2, which give a value of 7 instead of 7.5.</li>
          <li>Assigning a double value to a float variable, e.g. float f = IO.inputDouble(), which results in a loss of precision error. </li>
        </ol>
        <br/>
      </p>
      <p><u>BlueJ Project of the sample answer</u><br/><br/>
      You may download the BlueJ Project for the above sample answer <a href="/static/Lab_02_Sol.zip">here</a>.
      <br/>
    </p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
