<problem display_name="Lab 04 Graded Task 4" markdown="null" max_attempts="5" showanswer="past_due" submission_wait_seconds="5" weight="1.0">
  <text>
    <p>
      <u>Description</u>
    </p>
    <p>
In this lab exercise, you are tasked to complete the <b>playAgain()</b> method in the <b>Player</b> class. This method asks the user for some input, to determine whether to play the game again or not.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Instructions</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <ol>
        <li>
A loop should be used to complete this task.
</li>
        <li>
Declare a variable of type <b>char</b>. You can declare a <b>char</b> variable by coding:<br/>
<br/>
<pre>
char variableName;
</pre>
<br/>  
</li>
        <li>
Output a message on the terminal window to ask the user indicating if he/she wants to play the game again by entering the character <b>y</b> or <b>n</b>.
</li>
        <li>
Read the character from the user by using the <b>IO.inputCharacter()</b> method. Assign the read character to the declared <b>char</b> variable. 
</li>
        <li>
Check the character read from the user. If the character is neither <b>y</b> nor <b>Y</b> nor <b>n</b> nor <b>N</b>, ask the user to input again by repeating step 3.
</li>
        <li>
Otherwise, if the character is <b>y</b> or <b>Y</b>, return the value <b>true</b>, else return the value <b>false</b>. 
</li>
        <li>  
You can check if a <b>char</b> variable has a certain value by writing a Boolean expression. For example, suppose we have the <b>char</b> variable <i>input</i> and we want to check if it has a value of <b>a</b>, we can write the following Boolean expression:<br/>
<br/>
<pre>
input == 'a';
</pre>
<br/>
Suppose we want to check if its value is not equal to <b>a</b>, we can write the following Boolean expression:<br/>
<br/>
<pre>
input != 'a';
</pre>
<br/>
Notice the single quotes around the character a.<br/>
</li>
      </ol>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Testing</u>
    </p>
    <p>
A testing class, <b>Lab04GradedTask4</b>, has been prepared for you to test the implementation of the <b>playAgain()</b> method. To perform testing, right click on the <b>Lab04GradedTask4</b> class and then run the <b>testCase1()</b> method. The expected output of <b>testCase1()</b> is shown below.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Code in testCase1()</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <pre>
Player player = new Player();
boolean result = player.playAgain();
IO.outputln(result);
</pre>
    </p>
    <p>
      <u>Expect output of testCase1()</u>
    </p>
    <p><pre>
Want to play again? (y/n)
y
true
</pre><br/>
Notice that you don't need to enter the single quotes when enterting the character <b>y</b>.
</p>
    <p><pre>
Want to play again? (y/n)
k
Want to play again? (y/n)
</pre><br/>
Similar to character <b>y</b>, you don't need to enter the single quotes when entering the character <b>k</b>.
</p>
    <p>
  You are adviced to input characters other than <b>y</b> and <b>k</b> to test the correctness of the method.
</p>
    <p>
      <u>Coding Area</u>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img src="/static/lab04gt4.png" width="100%"/>
    </p>
  </text>
  <coderesponse queuename="hkust_java">
    <textbox rows="9" cols="80" mode="python" tabsize="4" label="lab04gt4input1"/>
    <codeparam>
      <initial_display>
// write your code after this line
</initial_display>
      <grader_payload>
{"refid": "/comp102x/lab04/ex04", "version":"V-01-20140716", "edge":false }
</grader_payload>
    </codeparam>
  </coderesponse>
  <solution>
    <div class="detailed-solution">
      <p>Explanation: </p>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Sample Answer</u>
        <br/>
      </p>
      <pre>
char playAgain;
        
do {

	IO.outputln("Want to play again? (y/n)");
	playAgain = IO.inputCharacter();

} while(playAgain ='n' &amp;&amp; playAgain ='y' &amp;&amp; playAgain ='N' &amp;&amp; playAgain ='Y');
                
return playAgain == 'y' || playAgain == 'Y';
</pre>
      <br/>
      <p>
        <u>Common Mistakes</u>
        <br/>
        <ol>
          <li>Wrong loop construct. The statement asking user for input is placed outside of the loop.</li>
          <li>Wrong loop condition. Please refer to <a href="https://courses.edx.org/courses/HKUSTx/COMP102x/2T2014/discussion/forum/i4x-HKUSTx-COMP102x-course-2014-LabExercises/threads/53d12b1d2b8b564977000f2f">this post</a> in the discussion forum for a detailed explanation.</li>
          <li>Missing a return statement for the method in one of the execution paths. In most cases, the return statement is written for the <b>if</b> case and the <b>else-if</b> case. However, it is omitted in the <b>else</b> case.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><u>BlueJ Project of the sample answer</u><br/><br/>
You may download the BlueJ Project for the above sample 

answer <a href="/static/Lab_04_Sol.zip">here</a>.
<br/>
</p>
    </div>
  </solution>
</problem>
